ALVIN NGUYEN: SOFTWARE ENGINEER

anguyen8613@gmail.com | (657) 334-9818 | LinkedIn | Portfolio Github

Primary Tech Stack: React, Node, Postgres, Express.

SUMMARY

Driven and experienced cloud based applications developer using key technologies and frameworks in Javascript. Experienced in joining and contributing to existing projects as well as starting a project from beginning to end including deployment and scheduled releases.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: Headless CMS, Data visualization, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, React, Redux, Next.js, jQuery, Styled Components, Tailwind CSS, SASS, AJAX, Adobe XD, Sketch, Figma

Back-End: Node, Express, Python, RESTful API, SQL, AWS Serverless Lambdas, Heroku, Postgres, Mongo, Oracle, Vercel, AWS EC2, Terraform, AWS S3, AWS Cloudwatch, Shell Scripts

Testing & Dev-Tools: Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Mocha, Chai, Git, GitHub, Jira, Chrome Dev Tools

WORK EXPERIENCE

Opentrons Pandemic Response Lab- *Software Engineer II* Jan 2022 - Feb 2023

- Responsible for automating workflows of new PCR Panels (Influenza, STI) using **Javascript/Typescript** and **React/Next.js**, leading to two new product offerings for our clinic and hospital clients
- Took ownership in writing backend api integration using Express, Open API, Postgres, AWS Lambda, Terraform, AWS S3, and AWS Cloud Watch to automate the PCR Lab and maximize efficiency of lab assistants. Increasing lab efficiency by 200%
- Manage production bugs as an on call first responder for **PagerDuty** incidents. Respond within 15 minutes to provide initial resolution with estimates on swiftness of hotfix
- Lead application releases to 3 different production environments: apply **database migrations**, apply **terraform** changes, apply code changes
- Lead key design and architecture meetings to add and refactor existing workflows
- Aligned with various team members ranging from engineering, product, design, and BI through daily and weekly stand-up, ticket grooming, retro, bug bash and deployment sessions
- Mentor junior engineers in various engineering and configuration tasks and reviewed pull requests

Softech Associates Inc- Software Engineer Sept 2018 - Dec 2021

- Develop full stack applications using React, Python, Java languages. Use existing libraries and frameworks: React, Next.js, Express, NodeJs, MongoDB, Oracle, Kendo, etc.
- Lead key design and architecture meetings to map **Oracle** databases with model objects of multiple software integrations
- Use **Jira** to work with the team to complete all stories in the current sprint
- Work with QA Team to demonstrate functionality and testing, bug fixing
- Work with the Run Team in critical releases to ensure the new code is deployed in production successfully
- Monitor and apply **hotfix** to the production environment backlog

Los Angeles Department of City Planning - *Software Engineer Intern* Sept 2017- May 2018

- Integrate a web map for automating the scoring process of transportation models
- Create dynamic components for the web map using CSS, HTML, Javascript, ¡Query
- Implement map functionality and shape file support using ESRI ArcGIS Javascript API
- Create a machine learning model for traffic collision reduction in Los Angeles

EDUCATION

California State University - Los Angeles Sep 2015- June 2018

Bachelors of Science - Computer Science